This call is now
being recorded.
All right.
I got the recorder
on and it's
February 22, 2023,
401pm and my name
is Scott and I'm
a defense
investigator and I
work for the
defense attorney
that represents
Lindsay Calhoun.
And did you catch
all that on the
phone?
Yes, I heard all
that.
Okay.
And could you
please identify
yourself?
This is Sergeant
Josh Windborn with
the Washington
State Patrol and I
do give you
permission to
record.
Great.
I appreciate it.
Thank you.
And thank you for
being available for
this phone call.
I know the case, we
kind of mentioned
this in the email.
This is a really
old case.
So it's just the
best of your memory
.
Maybe you don't
remember something,
you know, it's
totally fine.
Yeah.
I can tell you
right now I looked
at the report when
I got it and I did
not recall anything
of this aside from
what I can see what
I wrote up from the
report.
Okay.
That's a question.
I'll find it in the
report.
That makes sense.
So maybe let's see.
I had some notes
from something else
.
Do you have any
impressions though
on this back then
they were using,
was it the, it wasn
't
the dragger, but it
was the other?
The data master BAC
.
Data master.
Yeah.
Do you have any
opinion on maybe
the accuracy of the
data master versus
the dragger or the
draggers better?
The ones, you know,
the machines that
they are being
currently used, are
they better
than the ones that
you used to use?
I mean, I really
don't have opinion
either way.
They give me the
tool.
I just follow
directions on how
it works and that's
kind of what I do.
So, I have using
both.
I have yet to find
that it was, I
would say offered
like, I have to
have any issues
with
them.
Okay.
Let's see.
I'm trying to kind
of just shortcut a
little bit.
And back on this
time, back in 2011,
October 26, 2011,
did you have a dash
cam in your
car?
Do you remember?
Bear witness, thank
you.
And this came from
a collision, right?
To be honest with
you, I'm not sure
if I had a dash cam
at that time or not
.
Over my time, I did
have a one of the
older dash cam,
which is VHS, back
in the day.
And then obviously
got rid of that and
then eventually had
a, what we have now
, which is
the Coban system,
which I had for
quite a bit of time
.
I just don't recall
if back in 2011, if
I had a dash cam or
not, at that time.
Okay.
Let's check on my
notes here.
And then back with
the data master
versus the driver,
I have seen in some
reports where
sometimes the
machine will,
somebody will be
trying to give a
sample and it'll, I
don't
know, error out.
I'm not really sure
exactly what it is,
but that's, you
know, where a
trooper will have
to move to another
machine.
With the driver
error more than, or
the data master,
does that error
more than the
drivers
have?
I don't know, to be
honest with you, I
don't.
Like in your
experience, did the
data master ever
error out?
There had been like
, there had been
like very rare
occasions where it
had an error,
depending
on the situation, I
guess.
But obviously there
's different
situations where
there'd be
different errors.
But yeah, otherwise
if it gives you a
reading, then the
assumption is no
error.
Right.
Typically, if it
goes through the
process, that means
it's done through
check and balances
and that the
percentage is not
off by more than
that, whatever that
certain percentage
is between the two
breast samples and
the center, all the
checks.
So if it's got a
fail state,
obviously, so if
there was a problem
within the tracks,
then it would error
out and not allow
you to continue on.
Okay.
And then with the
dash cam, you said
you weren't sure.
Do you know if the,
with the retention
duration is on
those?
If there was video,
would that still be
available?
Do a normal public
records request?
Yeah, I'm not sure.
I know what the, I
'm not sure what the
retention period is
for it.
Okay.
I'm under the
assumption that the
retention period
for the report
itself had already
come
and gone.
It might have been
like a 10 year, but
I'm not the public
disclosure person.
They know that.
They know more than
I do about that
stuff.
So it's, like, I'm
not sure if the
videos are the same
as the paperwork,
but, and I'm
looking at, I'm
doing a little bit
of reasserting bear
with me.
As I fumble through
here, I was trying
to pull up a little
research to see if
maybe I
had something that
would tell me if I
had a dash cam at
the time.
And so I went to my
tar, which is our
daily activity,
time activity
report that we do
every day when we
work.
It keeps track of
traffic stops,
collisions,
everything,
everything that we
come in contact
with, with somebody
or doing something,
it keeps track of
our time.
And on that tar, we
usually also keep
track of, like
camera check times
and stuff.
So if I had, if I
had co-banned for a
camera back at that
time, I would have
to do a check,
pre-check of the
camera before my
shift starts to
make sure that it's
operating correctly
.
And so I am looking
at the tar, but it
doesn't list, it
doesn't show
anything on the
back.
Whether there is,
they didn't show a
camera check time,
but it also doesn't
show a radar
check time, it
doesn't show my
patrol vehicle
license.
All these things
are things that I
would normally put
on my tar every day
.
So my assumption is
that at one point
we want from paper
tar to electronic
tar, and so
it might have
probably been like
a paper tar from
back then and
submitted into the
system.
And this is how we
submitted it.
Okay, and then it
looks like the only
FST that was done,
let's see, there
was an HTN done.
And then I'm
assuming, pretty
much nothing
outside of it.
So like she had a
cast on her foot,
but she was able to
stand there, like
that was the
one thing she could
do, she could stand
, you know, with her
shoulders, I don't
know, level.
Right, yeah, so she
was able to stand
to do the
horizontal and
stagnant test, but
because
of the cast and she
said that she'd
hurt her, obviously
wearing a cast, but
she'd hurt
her friend or ankle
from tripping over
a dog.
Do you remember if
it was like a
walking cast, or
did she have crut
ches or something to
assist?
I do not recall.
Okay.
And then she stated
no to whether or
not she drank any
alcohol, but she
said she had
taken prescription
medication, Paxil.
And how did you
training in the
experience?
Is that a
medication that can
affect driving?
I do not know.
And at the time
that she told me, I
don't think I knew
if Paxil was an
impairing type
medication or not.
Do you recall if
there was any
occupants with her?
Was she the only
one in the car?
Yeah, she was the
only one.
Okay.
And then it looks
like, just the
overall, your
report indicates
that she was pretty
cooperative.
She understood when
you went over and
applied consent and
her constitutional
rights.
Yeah.
Did the other
driver recall when
you contacted them,
did they have
suspicion or did
they
suspect that this
other driver that
rear ended them was
possibly under the
influence?
Um, let me see.
Uh, not that I
recall, there's
nothing more to
force it indicates
that that was the
case.
Okay, and then the
original dispatch
call, you say, the
WSP Communications
Advise of
a collision
partially blocking
the ramp.
Do you know if the
call came in from
one of the people
involved in the
collision or was
it just a passerby?
I do not recall.
Um, I think that
might be just about
it then.
As far as, yeah, I
mean there wasn't a
whole...
Let me see.
Do you recall if
she seemed kind of
like down into
practice, was she
crying or emotional
?
I'm looking at the
checkbox of the
peer-res
observations and it
's not...
Yeah, I just, I
just looked at her
and she, she was
like, she's
cooperative and all
that
stuff.
And then I was just
going to do my
report real quick
and skim it to see
if I saw anything.
Okay.
Yeah, all right, I
think that's it.
Uh, I really
appreciate it.
Um, I doubt there
will be any follow-
up, but yeah, I'll
let the attorney
know what we went
over and hopefully
that should be it.
Sure.
I appreciate it.
Thank you very much
.
Yes, no problem.
Alright, have a
good one.
You too.
Bye.